First, let's take a look at the overall distribution of the pressure chart when we press the Alt key.
After the pressure chart is turned on, the grid color will be changed according to its strength.
The red area is the tightest position, the blue area is the widest position,
and the green area is the tightest position.
When we make tight clothes, it is best to ensure that most of them are green or blue,
and the visual effect is relatively close.
Next, we will learn how to deal with this area on the back.
Here we use the check tool.
It is in the tool group of the internal drawing pattern.
We can click and drag on the board.
We want to make sure that the widest position of the zero is near the waist.
After loosening the mouse, we will see that two zero holes are dug on the waist.
After that, we will use the line tool to sew the two sides of the zero hole together.
This will save part of the space on the board,
so that the whole board is more three-dimensional and more in line with the structure of our human body.
Then we use the line tool to sew the two sides together and start the simulation.
As you can see, there is more space on the board because the waist is dug,
so it is very much in line with the structure of our human body.
Here we will see that it may have some sharp corners.
As long as we pull the rope a little longer,
we can make it a little more natural.
Here we consider that later we are going to make the costume of the rabbit girl.
It may be cut more flat in the back here,
so I move the point of the rope down a little bit.
In addition, we can also use the ruler.
Remember that the shrinkage rate should be set to negative,
so that we can tighten a certain part of the board.
So that we can polish it at the point of the rope.
After opening the model, it looks flat because the grid shrinks.
Next, we can change the perspective and see if there are any problems with this dress.
The first one is the sleeve.
The curve of the sleeve here does not seem to be related.
For example, when we change to the back,
it is obvious that there is more here.
If we don't have some movement in our hands,
this part will actually be affected.
So we can use the 3D board tool to draw a curve here.
Click on the point of the shoulder,
then press the Ctrl key to create a curve point.
Loosen the Ctrl key,
we can create a straight line point.
Double click on the end position.
Here we will find that there is a sharp corner at the bottom of the page.
In the process of making clothes,
we try to make the side of it a flat corner.
So when drawing this line, we have to pay attention to it.
After that, we can use the built-in multidirectional line tool
to draw a cut line along this reference line.
In the process of making clothes,
it is also the same.
Click on the start button first,
then press the Ctrl key to create a curve point.
In addition to this method,
we can also use the edit line tool.
Select this line,
right-click,
there is a curve inside the curve,
or a curve inside the curve.
If you choose to change to the inner curve,
the original 3D line will not appear.
And this line will be converted to the inner curve.
In this case,
we can use this inner curve
to make subsequent cuts.
Here is also the same,
choose to convert to the inner curve.
Then we zoom in,
pay attention to this inner curve point,
move to the outside of the board,
or the point above the outside of the board.
The inner curve must be in contact with the outside of the board
to be able to cut the board.
Then we can see that
this inner curve point
is open.
In the process of adjustment,
we can use the edit curve point function
to adjust the curve of this curve more smoothly.
Then we can choose to cut
after choosing this inner curve.
In this way,
we can delete the excess boards.
Sometimes when we are closer to the camera,
or when a board is smaller,
we will see that
the part outside the board line
is still white.
This part is actually the face of our grid.
The face of the grid is more than the outside of the board line.
In fact,
it is because our particle diameter is too large.
If we reduce the particle diameter,
it will not look so obvious.
Then,
we switch back to the black and white surface
or the texture surface here.
Then,
we use the same method
to operate the back sleeve here.
The back sleeve is the same as the back sleeve,
the part inside the board line is the same as the front,
so that the part outside the board line
is the same as the part inside the board line.
After the simulation,
we now deal with
other problems of this skirt.
First of all,
we can clearly see that
its front,
which looks like a sleeve,
is very big,
and there are two obvious folds.
After looking at the transparent picture, we will see that there is actually a small part in the bottom of the page.
So we can adjust the bottom of the page separately and put it in a little bit.
For the modification of the curve line here, we need to press the Ctrl key to move along the original melody.
And while pressing the Ctrl key to move, press the mouse button and the right key to enter the specific number.
I tried 15 mm here first.
Then how do we judge if it is attached?
We can pull the view a little bit to the top of the head to take a look.
When we modify the curve line on this side, that is, press the Ctrl key to move this point.
After moving, when we open the simulation, you can see from the top that its side is actually very close to the human body.
So now what we are going to deal with is that there is a very obvious fold on the side here.
Here we use a fake needle to click on the two sides of this opening.
After combining this fold, we will see that the curve line is now relatively close to the body curve of Hana.
So we can think of the way we created in the previous back piece.
Then here we can also add a line to combine its two sides.
So now we are going to choose to add a line tool.
In the middle position of these two fake needles, click to create a division point.
Then right-click to choose to add a line.
After choosing to add a line, we can refer to this fake line just now.
Then here we modify its width to 40.
The fake line we created just now is about 40.
Then don't change the other values first.
Then here we can see that this line point is close to the most protruding point of the chest.
Then delete the fake needle just now with the edit fake line.
Then here our breast line only opens to the widest point.
The widest point is also easy to understand.
Because the position of the chest is the widest, the material it needs is definitely the most.
So this triangle can be dug to the most prominent point of the chest.
After opening the pattern, the whole dress is now relatively close to the curve of the human body.
Now that the shape of the large body is almost the same, we can reduce the strength and conflict thickness of the chest.
Then let's take a look at the space here on the waist.
In fact, you can see that there is still some volume on the upper abdomen.
After turning the angle, you will find that there is actually not much volume on the back here.
Most of the volume is on the front.
So we can use the edit sheet tool to close the front waist to 10 mm, which is 1 cm.
In fact, it is a very small amount.
Because we can see that there is still a little volume on the lower abdomen.
Let's remove this part of the volume first.
When making tight clothes, you must be patient and adjust it a little bit.
But now if we adjust the point of the waist in a large extent, it is no longer useful.
Because we will only affect the area near the waist.
It cannot be adjusted to the chest to the waist in a large area.
So we have to change one way, which is to increase the length.
Here we withdraw the large-distance adjustment that was just demonstrated.
Go back to the position of about 10 mm.
Here we have two creation methods.
One is still the same as before.
After selecting the adjustment tool, click and drag the mouse.
There is another way.
After we select the adjustment tool,
when the mouse is located at the bottom of the chest,
and at the same level as the side point of the waist,
click the mouse, click the mouse left button,
and the specific creation value will pop up.
When creating a rope,
you must pay attention to the width of the left and right sides is equal.
For the length, we can use the default value here.
We first open a width of 10 mm on the left side,
and a width of 10 mm on the right side.
This is actually equivalent to the waist being 2 cm in one side,
and the whole front will be 4 cm in the other side.
Then we sew the two sides together with the sewing tool.
After sewing, the overall structure can be seen to be very close.
If you think it's not close enough,
we can widen the seam allowance.
Using the adjustment tool,
we can select the shape of the entire seam allowance.
After selecting, the point in the middle of the double machine can be used as the center point.
In this way, when we modify its width,
it will be modified with the center point as the standard to the two sides.
We can slightly widen it.
If the seam allowance is wider,
it will be easy to have protruding problems.
Here,
we can use the ruler to align it.
Or we can make the seam allowance a little narrower.
Or we can make the seam allowance a little longer.
Here,
because I consider the side,
we have to do some fold effect later.
So I choose to return to the seam allowance without modification.